Curriculum Vitae

Name: Kahlil Lechelt

Adresse: Ruhrstr. 15, 70374 Stuttgart, Germany

Telefon: +49 (0)163 461 25 75

E-Mail: hello@kahlil.info
Web: http://kahlil.info

Geburtsdatum: 01/08/1978



Summary

After three years of full stack development with PHP, MySQL, JavaScript and CSS now three years leading the front-end side of big and small client projects at ETECTURE. Gives internal trainings on topics like GruntJS and Git.

Propagates modular programming of JavaScript and CSS. Takes care of Frontend Operations with GruntJS or GulpJS. Uses AngularJS for bigger applications, Sass or Less to preprocess CSS and Jade to preprocess HTML.

Co-organizer of KarlsruheJS and FrankfurtJS, speaker on the first EnterJS in Germany. Host of the interview podcast "Descriptive" with guests from the JavaScript and web development world. Teaches himself new JavaScript frameworks in his free time. So far: AngularJS, EmberJS and AmpersandJS. Favors CommonJS and Browserify when it comes to JavaScript modules.

Very interested in product development with JavaScript and Frontend Ops.

Skills

Sprachen/Frameworks/Tools

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Less
- Sass
- AngularJS
- jQuery
- iQuery Plugin Development
- GruntJS
- GulpJS
- GruntJS Plugin Development
- Git
- Node.js

- Node Module Development
- Jade
- Browserify
- Require.js
- Hoodie
- AmpersandJS
- EmberJS
- BackboneJS
- Templating in Liferay
- Templating in Shopware
- Templating in Oxid
- Templating and component development for CQ5
- PHP
- MySQL
- Kirby CMS
- Contao

Software

• Server: Apache

• PC: Windows, Mac (strongly favored), Linux

• Editor: Sublime Text, Atom

• Versioning: Git

Beruflicher Werdegang

01/2014 bis heute: Co-organizer of FrankfurtJS

09/2013 bis heute: Co-organizer of KarlsruheJS

09/2011 bis heute: Software Developer Fronten-End at ETECTURE

- Leading the front-end development part of big and small client projects
- Frontend Ops with GruntJS
- Determination of front-end architecture for various projects
- · Programming:
 - JavaScript: jQuery, AngularJS, jQuery Mobile
 - CSS: Sass, Less, SMACSS to modularize, responsive websites, Bootstrap, PureCSS

- GruntJS configuration and plugin development
- Git for versioning

01/2009 bis 08/2011: Freelancer on the side1

- Extension development for Contao project
- Programming jQuery, CSS3, HTML5

07/2010 bis 08/2011: Webentwickler bei BrainFactory in Stuttgart

- Project management
- Implementation of full projects with Contao
- HTML5, CSS3, LESS CSS, Contao, TYPO3

07/2008 bis 06/2010: Web Developer at FARO GmbH & Co. KG

Full stack implementation of microsites with TYPO3, Contao and jQuery

04/2008 bis 07/2008: Job search and move from Leipzig to Stuttgart

08/2006 - 03/2008: Musician, singer in the Reggae/Dancehall genre in Leipzig

- Released one EP and two albums
- On tour in Europe and Japan

Studium

08/2006: Graduation from FH Giessen-Friedberg

03/2004 - 09/2004: Internship at media agency MellowMessage in Leipzig

09/2001: Studies in economy and computer science at FH Giessen-Friedberg

2000 – 2001: Studies in media and computer science at Hochschule für Druck u. Medien in Stuttgart

1999 – 2000: Studies in Ethnologie and Französich at Universität Tübingen

Schulausbildung

1998 – 1999: Various little jobs

1989 - 1998: Hegel-Gymnasium in Stuttgart-Vaihingen

1988 - 1989: Robert-Koch Realschule in Stuttgart-Vaihingen

1984 – 1988: Pestalozzischule in Stuttgart-Vaihingen

Languages

German – native tongue English – fluent Französisch – good